<section id="showcases-dynamvc">
	<title>Spring MVC Controllers implemented in a dynamic language</title>
	<para>
		This small application showcases implementing Spring MVC Controllers
		using the dynamic language support introduced in Spring 2.0.
	</para>

	<para>
		The web application is <emphasis>very</emphasis> simplistic, because the
		intent is to convey the basics of the dynamic language support as applied to
		Spring MVC and pretty much nothing else.
	</para>

	<para>
		There is one Groovy file in the application. It is called
		'FortuneController.groovy' and it is located in the 'war/WEB-INF/groovy'
		folder. This Groovy script file is referenced by the 'fortune'
		bean in the 'war/WEB-INF/fortune-servlet.xml' Spring MVC configuration file.
	</para>

	<para>
		You will notice that the 'fortune' bean is set as refreshable via the use
		of the 'refresh-check-delay' attribute on the &lt;lang:groovy/&gt; element. The
		value of this attribute is set to '3000' which means that changes to the
		'FortuneController.groovy' file will be picked up after a delay of 3 seconds.
	</para>

	<para>
		If you deploy the application to Tomcat (for example), you can then go into
		the exploded '/WEB-INF/groovy' folder and edit the 'FortuneController.groovy'
		file directly. Any such changes that you make will be picked up automatically
		and the 'fortune' bean will be reconfigured... all without having to stop,
		redeploy and restart the application. Try it yourself... now admittedly
		there is not a lot of complex logic in the 'FortuneController.groovy' file
		(which is good because Controllers in Spring MVC should be as thin as possible).
	</para>

	<para>
		You could try returning a default Fortune instead of delegating to the injected
		FortuneService, or you could return a different logical view name, or
		(if you are feeling more ambitious) you could try creating a custom
		Groovy implementation of the FortuneService interface and try plugging that into
		the web application. Perhaps your custom Groovy FortuneService could access
		a web service to get some Fortunes, or apply some different randomizing logic
		to the returned Fortune, or whatever. The key point is that you will be able to make
		these changes without having to redeploy (or bounce) your application. This is
		a great boon with regard to rapid prototyping.
	</para>

	<section id="showcases-dynamvc-build">
		<title>Build and deployment</title>
		<para>
			The <emphasis>samples/showcases/dynamvc</emphasis> directory contains the web-app
			source. For deployment, it needs to be built with Apache Ant. The only requirements
			are JDK >=1.4 (it is Groovy that requires at a minimum JDK 1.4) and Ant >=1.5.
		</para>

		<para>
			Run "build.bat" in this directory for available targets (e.g. "build.bat build",
			"build.bat warfile"). Note that to start Ant this way, you'll need an XML parser
			in your classpath (e.g. in "%JAVA_HOME%/jre/lib/ext"; included in JDK 1.4). You can
			use "warfile.bat" as a shortcut for WAR file creation. The WAR file will be created
			in the "dist" directory.
		</para>
	</section>

</section>
